<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-15T15:48:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ayyybel’s Emporium</title><subtitle>My personal site</subtitle><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><entry><title type="html">Mourn while it matters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mourn-while-it-matters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mourn while it matters" /><published>2025-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mourn%20while%20it%20matters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mourn-while-it-matters/"><![CDATA[<p>I think we should always be in mourning. Not for things that have passed, but for the things we have. If we are aware of their eventual passing, and remind ourselves of it occasionally, it makes us appreciate the things and people around us so much more. The most painful and regretful passings I’ve experienced were for the people and things I didn’t think to appreciate.</p>

<p>It also makes it less painful when people pass or things disappear. Not because you’ve done all the mourning that needs to be done ahead of time, but because you spent more time truly appreciating them.</p>

<p>Knowing everything and everyone will go eventually also imposes a sense of intentionality to how you spend your time. If you know a family member is passing soon, you’ll spend more time with them. When people find out they are going to die, they begin to appreciate what they love that much more. Cancer victims with months left to live will shift their entire lives to do the things they want to do. Often, I believe reminding yourself that you have a limited amount of time can instill a similar appreciation and sense of urgency that pushes people to live the lives they actually want to live.</p>

<p>It’s much more painful to lose someone if it’s a surprise. Forgetting the mortality of the ones you love means you spend more time taking them for granted, and you wish you had more time because of it. Of course, if you had had more time, it wouldn’t have changed anything, because you wouldn’t have been reminded of their mortality. Knowing and reminding yourself on a regular basis that every relationship, experience, routine, and person is temporary is an immensely grounding practice.</p>

<p>It allows you to look to your future, past unpleasant situations, as well as reminds you to fully appreciate the present. Blinding yourself to the changing nature of the world can be comforting, sure, but it is ultimately harmful to yourself in the long term when that change sneaks up on you.</p>

<p>Realistic planning, prioritization of your dreams, and spontaneity all suffer when you fail to acknowledge the things that will change in your life. It’s impossible to plan for the future when you refuse to believe that the future will be significantly different than the present. If you allow yourself to forget how little time we have to do the things we want, they will get put off for decades. Assuming tomorrow will be the same as today puts no pressure on you to do something spontaneous, as it could be done any day in the future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think we should always be in mourning. Not for things that have passed, but for the things we have. If we are aware of their eventual passing, and remind ourselves of it occasionally, it makes us appreciate the things and people around us so much more. The most painful and regretful passings I’ve experienced were for the people and things I didn’t think to appreciate.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adventures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adventures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures" /><published>2025-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adventures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adventures/"><![CDATA[<p>There are a few different kinds of adventures. I think there are 3. But first, what makes an outing an adventure? I think it has to do with the aspect of a challenge. It’s got to have some kind of goal that you aren’t sure you can achieve. It’s not an adventure if there’s nothing to turn back from. It doesn’t necessarily have to be risky, though that’s a common challenge. Another kind could be discomfort. It could be wet or cold or hot or humid or otherwise just kinda uncomfortable in some way. That it might make you not succeed at the goal is what makes it an adventure. Now, for the kinds of adventure.</p>

<p>There are societal adventures. These are adventures in to a part of society or culture that you would never otherwise experience. Going to a city in a new country, spending a weekend in the big city, that kind of thing. The challenge might come from the social anxiety confronted, the risks associated with being in an unfamiliar place, or the embarrassment of interacting with others poorly.</p>

<p>There are natural adventures. These are adventures into nature. Experiencing new parts of nature, going to the mountains or the coast, sleeping in the woods or in a field getting out there. I think natural adventures are the most classical kind of adventure. Testing oneself against whatever is out there. The challenge in natural adventures generally comes from the risks and discomfort of the elements, the flora, and the fauna.</p>

<p>Finally, there are relationship-based adventures. Activities you undertake with a goal in mind with another person, where the goal pertains to what is developed between you. I think this is a whole other ballgame, and a lot harder to define. It’s still an adventure, but the risks are a bit more intangible. They involve the continuation &amp; nature of the relationship, social fallout, and other stuff like that.</p>

<p>I think it’s good to try and do some kind of adventure as often as you can. The overcoming of an obstacle, the learning of a new skill, the honing of a craft, or any number of other things you need to get through an adventure will benefit you in your daily life. Without discomfort and challenge, how can we grow as people? This will undoubtedly mean failing, but that’s still learning, possibly more so than succeeding. There’s no way to know your limit until you reach it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are a few different kinds of adventures. I think there are 3. But first, what makes an outing an adventure? I think it has to do with the aspect of a challenge. It’s got to have some kind of goal that you aren’t sure you can achieve. It’s not an adventure if there’s nothing to turn back from. It doesn’t necessarily have to be risky, though that’s a common challenge. Another kind could be discomfort. It could be wet or cold or hot or humid or otherwise just kinda uncomfortable in some way. That it might make you not succeed at the goal is what makes it an adventure. Now, for the kinds of adventure.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blog rules</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog-rules/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog rules" /><published>2025-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog%20rules</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog-rules/"><![CDATA[<p>I think this blog will have 2 main kinds of posts: essays and updates. Essays will follow the rules below, while updates are more casual, basically just Instagram posts.</p>

<p>This is the set of rules I am making for my own personal blog. I think they serve a useful purpose in preserving and protecting the things I write from my future self, as well as creating guidelines to facilitate creating more. These are in no particular order, and really only apply to my essays.</p>

<h2 id="rule-1">Rule 1</h2>

<p>Don’t edit, don’t delete<br />
	This rule might be one of the hardest to follow. It’s hard to read something written by my past self and not change something or want to get rid of it all together. Unfortunately, while I want this blog to change and grow, I also want you to be able to see the ways that I have changed and grown as a person and a writer. 
	Almost more importantly than that though, if something can be edited in the future, it’s never truly done. I want my works to be done when I decide they are, so I can move on to other things.</p>

<h2 id="rule-2">Rule 2</h2>

<p>Write for an audience<br />
	Aka, dance like someone’s watching. While I doubt this blog will ever get much traffic, I want it to be a blog and not a journal. I already have a journal to journal in. As such, I want my blog posts to be edited, semi-professional, and as well written as I am capable of.</p>

<h2 id="rule-3">Rule 3</h2>

<p>This blog does not have a topic, but it is strictly non-professional.<br />
	This is a blog about my interests, not a job application or any kind of pitch for employment. The reasoning behind this rule is to address a conundrum I’ve had with this website, deciding whether it is personal or professional. Through this rule, I am making this blog and this site a place for me to express myself, devoid of the need to make money or cater to anyone.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think this blog will have 2 main kinds of posts: essays and updates. Essays will follow the rules below, while updates are more casual, basically just Instagram posts.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Altar to organization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/altar-to-organization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Altar to organization" /><published>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/altar%20to%20organization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/altar-to-organization/"><![CDATA[<p>Your clean clothes are migrating from chair to bed to chair and your life is in shambles.
You lose your phone, your wallet, and your jewelry. You frantically clean before every unsuccessful date. You’ve always thought of an organized room as the minimalist, sanitized, color-coordinated ones you see on Pinterest. I have bad news: you and I, along with most, are not minimalist, sanitized people. Our lives are messy, dirty, and full of junk. That won’t change, but what can change is how we interact with our things.</p>

<p>I invite you to look at your space as a neighborhood. There’s research that shows people won’t litter in a space that they see as clean. The point of the organizational ritual is to create a neighborhood you don’t want to litter in, and systems to make it easy to avoid doing. It’s all about minimizing the effort needed to stay organized in the future. That might sound unrealistic, but I promise this is not a Mary Kondo-change-your-life task.</p>

<p>Everyone can have a systematized space. From the sailor, who keeps every item locked in place on the rolling ocean, to the soldier, who needs every item they own accessible, to the artist, well — maybe not the artist. Many walks of life come to study under the holy practice of organizing.</p>

<p>I offer 5 commandments for your studies, in order of importance:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Every item needs a home.</li>
  <li>Sometimes, a home is a junk drawer.</li>
  <li>Mold your space to your system.</li>
  <li>Find your organizational votives.</li>
  <li>An organized space is not always a tidy one.</li>
</ol>

<p>A home is an assigned spot an item can return to when not being used. It must be a dedicated storage location. When an item is in its home, it can stay there. It doesn’t need to be moved when the room is cleaned, a new project is started, or another item needs to be reached.</p>

<p>When something is missing a home, it becomes a floater in your space. It moves from bed to desk to chair to floor. It causes a chaotic spark that makes it harder for other items to find their homes and descends your space into a cacophony of lost pens and stepped on clothes.</p>

<p>For the transient item, like a battery or a half used notepad, a junk drawer can be a home. It allows you to keep a little pocket of disorganization without the spark of chaos. A necessary evil and a home for the perpetually troubled and troublesome trinket. Just keep it contained, and keep it small, or it will threaten to tip you backwards into the mess.</p>

<p>Your space can become a part of your organization system. Hang your life on your walls. Install some floating shelves (it’s not as hard as you think, even with your two left hands.) Create a space that forces you to return things to their homes lest it drive you mad from inconvenience.</p>

<p>In molding your space to your system, you will find your votives. The items that allow you to pray at the altar of organization. Allow push pins and binder clips to become the body and blood of your new martyr. Perform your organizational prayer with the items that suit you. Once you find these, keep them stocked, and in their own special home.</p>

<p>Finally, know in your heart that an organized space is not always a tidy one. Do not strive for the unrealistic standards portrayed in the media. Eventually, you will settle on your own unique system. Or maybe not. I’m not your mother.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your clean clothes are migrating from chair to bed to chair and your life is in shambles. You lose your phone, your wallet, and your jewelry. You frantically clean before every unsuccessful date. You’ve always thought of an organized room as the minimalist, sanitized, color-coordinated ones you see on Pinterest. I have bad news: you and I, along with most, are not minimalist, sanitized people. Our lives are messy, dirty, and full of junk. That won’t change, but what can change is how we interact with our things.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflections on a year of biking to work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reflections-on-a-year-of-biking-to-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflections on a year of biking to work" /><published>2024-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reflections%20on%20a%20year%20of%20biking%20to%20work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reflections-on-a-year-of-biking-to-work/"><![CDATA[<p>Starting in July 2023, I biked to work five days a week, for about 2 miles each way. That comes out to somewhere around 1000 miles, maybe a bit less accounting for sick days and incidental and occasional (but appreciated) rides from my girlfriend. With a total of two bikes used (the first was stolen) this was absolutely economical and enjoyable.</p>

<p>Granted, my bicycle commute is possibly one of the most idyllic in America. Almost entirely on a designated path along a river, only on a road for the final ~30 yards. This wasn’t on accident though. I chose my apartment exclusively because of the proximity and pleasantness of the commute, and likely paid extra for it. That was a non-negotiable part of my housing choice.</p>

<p>I did this every day, rain or shine, snow or sleet, and I think some of my favorite days were the ones with the worst weather. A few highlights:</p>

<p>Drenching rain in a t-shirt soaked to the bone, passing a similarly dressed runner absolutely beaming the same way I was as my music blasted in my ears and I sprinted the full 2 miles.</p>

<p>A late freeze in January with temperatures in the teens and a thin layer of ice on the trail. Any time I put too much force into the pedals my rear wheel would spin out. Fell three times during this freeze but wouldn’t trade the experience for a more pleasant one.</p>

<p>Getting passed by a full racing peloton on my casual ride to work, and completely gassing myself to almost keep up for a few minutes.</p>

<p>None of these experiences were advisable, but they were all fulfilling, enjoyable, and mine.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting in July 2023, I biked to work five days a week, for about 2 miles each way. That comes out to somewhere around 1000 miles, maybe a bit less accounting for sick days and incidental and occasional (but appreciated) rides from my girlfriend. With a total of two bikes used (the first was stolen) this was absolutely economical and enjoyable.]]></summary></entry></feed>