<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-14T15:01:55-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ayyybel’s Emporium</title><subtitle>My personal site</subtitle><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><entry><title type="html">Blog rules</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog-rules/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog rules" /><published>2025-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog%20rules</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog-rules/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the set of rules I am making for my own personal blog. I think they serve a useful purpose in preserving and protecting the things I write from my future self, as well as creating guidelines to facilitate creating more. These are in no particular order. All rules should be followed, and if they aren’t, tell me.</p>

<h2 id="rule-1">Rule 1</h2>
<p>Don’t edit, don’t delete
	This rule might be one of the hardest to follow. It’s hard to read something written by my past self and not change something or want to get rid of it all together. Unfortunately, while I want this blog to change and grow, I also want you to be able to see the ways that I have changed and grown as a person and a writer. 
	Almost more importantly than that though, if something can be edited in the future, it’s never truly done. I want my works to be done when I decide they are, so I can move on to other things.</p>
<h2 id="rule-2">Rule 2</h2>
<p>Write for an audience
	Aka, dance like someone’s watching. While I doubt this blog will ever get much traffic, I want it to be a blog and not a journal. I already have a journal to journal in. As such, I want my blog posts to be edited, semi-professional, and as well written as I am capable of.</p>
<h2 id="rule-3">Rule 3</h2>
<p>This blog does not have a topic, but it is strictly non-professional.
	This is a blog about my interests, not a job application or any kind of pitch for employment. This blog is divorced from capital and it’s acquisition outside of itself. If I get a readership, I may monetize it for what it is, but it won’t be used to get me other jobs. The reasoning behind this rule is to address a conundrum I’ve had with this website, deciding whether it is personal or professional. Through this rule, I am making this blog and this site a place for me to express myself, devoid of the need to make money or cater to anyone.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the set of rules I am making for my own personal blog. I think they serve a useful purpose in preserving and protecting the things I write from my future self, as well as creating guidelines to facilitate creating more. These are in no particular order. All rules should be followed, and if they aren’t, tell me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Legacy for the hopelessly ambitious</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/legacy-for-the-hopelessly-ambitious/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Legacy for the hopelessly ambitious" /><published>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/legacy%20for%20the%20hopelessly%20ambitious</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/legacy-for-the-hopelessly-ambitious/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a little bit macabre that someone my age, 23, is thinking about legacy with much intensity. It should be a topic for the elderly, the older, and those who’ve accomplished something. One should begin thinking about legacy in their donations to colleges, not as they graduate from them.</p>

<p>It’s prompted, I believe more and more, by the aggressiveness by which we are swallowed by the cultural consciousness. By the temporality of everything being done at the moment. The need to be seen and make a mark is stronger than ever, and I think it’s part of what is driving people to higher and higher extremes. In a room where everyone is screaming, how can one be heard?</p>

<p>I think the true, most effective answer is that you ignore the room. You find a small group or community, and without making so much as a ripple in the screaming ocean of the culture, you leave a strong mark on a select few that will be felt for years.</p>

<p>The problem with that, of course, is that once one has been exposed to the screaming ocean, seen the heights that can be reached, such a small impact no longer feels like enough. Our expectations are scaled out of proportion with our fates, and our instinct is to strive for the greatest heights possible, ignoring the smaller, attainable, and comfortable peaks on the way.</p>

<p>If you shoot for the moon and you miss, you’ll end up in the void, freezing and forgotten.</p>

<p>This leaves us with a problem. Countless hopelessly ambitious individuals with no interest in the small stuff. The dreamers, I’ve seen them called. They are championed in our advertising, encouraged to keep dreaming bigger and bigger, with the newest SaaS solution to support them. And so they dream, bigger and bigger, their ideas growing larger and more impressive, and when they look back after they’ve created their masterpieces, there’s no one watching.</p>

<p>It’s always been our problem, as a species. In the more distant past, we couldn’t choose what would be preserved for posterity. Whatever fell into a peat bog or happened to be made of the right concrete or depicted the right religion was saved, for the future to learn from. We used to rely on luck to determine what the future would know of us.</p>

<p>Now, in an age where our net output of information is scaling exponentially, we are using something’s ability to capture attention en masse to determine if it should be saved. At least it’s better than pure luck, but there’s no way it’s preserving our best.</p>

<p>This form of legacy - our creations’ survival into the future - has created a twisted incentive, where in order to be remembered, we need to create something that will capture the most attention possible. When something is created only to capture attention, not provide value, we have a problem where things that aren’t useful are preserved, and things of real importance are forgotten in their place.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a little bit macabre that someone my age, 23, is thinking about legacy with much intensity. It should be a topic for the elderly, the older, and those who’ve accomplished something. One should begin thinking about legacy in their donations to colleges, not as they graduate from them.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Altar to organization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/altar-to-organization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Altar to organization" /><published>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/altar%20to%20organization</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/altar-to-organization/"><![CDATA[<p>Your clean clothes are migrating from chair to bed to chair and your life is in shambles.
You lose your phone, your wallet, and your jewelry. You frantically clean before every unsuccessful date. You’ve always thought of an organized room as the minimalist, sanitized, color-coordinated ones you see on Pinterest. I have bad news: you and I, along with most, are not minimalist, sanitized people. Our lives are messy, dirty, and full of junk. That won’t change, but what can change is how we interact with our things.</p>

<p>I invite you to look at your space as a neighborhood. There’s research that shows people won’t litter in a space that they see as clean. The point of the organizational ritual is to create a neighborhood you don’t want to litter in, and systems to make it easy to avoid doing. It’s all about minimizing the effort needed to stay organized in the future. That might sound unrealistic, but I promise this is not a Mary Kondo-change-your-life task.</p>

<p>Everyone can have a systematized space. From the sailor, who keeps every item locked in place on the rolling ocean, to the soldier, who needs every item they own accessible, to the artist, well — maybe not the artist. Many walks of life come to study under the holy practice of organizing.</p>

<p>I offer 5 commandments for your studies, in order of importance:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Every item needs a home.</li>
  <li>Sometimes, a home is a junk drawer.</li>
  <li>Mold your space to your system.</li>
  <li>Find your organizational votives.</li>
  <li>An organized space is not always a tidy one.</li>
</ol>

<p>A home is an assigned spot an item can return to when not being used. It must be a dedicated storage location. When an item is in its home, it can stay there. It doesn’t need to be moved when the room is cleaned, a new project is started, or another item needs to be reached.</p>

<p>When something is missing a home, it becomes a floater in your space. It moves from bed to desk to chair to floor. It causes a chaotic spark that makes it harder for other items to find their homes and descends your space into a cacophony of lost pens and stepped on clothes.</p>

<p>For the transient item, like a battery or a half used notepad, a junk drawer can be a home. It allows you to keep a little pocket of disorganization without the spark of chaos. A necessary evil and a home for the perpetually troubled and troublesome trinket. Just keep it contained, and keep it small, or it will threaten to tip you backwards into the mess.</p>

<p>Your space can become a part of your organization system. Hang your life on your walls. Install some floating shelves (it’s not as hard as you think, even with your two left hands.) Create a space that forces you to return things to their homes lest it drive you mad from inconvenience.</p>

<p>In molding your space to your system, you will find your votives. The items that allow you to pray at the altar of organization. Allow push pins and binder clips to become the body and blood of your new martyr. Perform your organizational prayer with the items that suit you. Once you find these, keep them stocked, and in their own special home.</p>

<p>Finally, know in your heart that an organized space is not always a tidy one. Do not strive for the unrealistic standards portrayed in the media. Eventually, you will settle on your own unique system. Or maybe not. I’m not your mother.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your clean clothes are migrating from chair to bed to chair and your life is in shambles. You lose your phone, your wallet, and your jewelry. You frantically clean before every unsuccessful date. You’ve always thought of an organized room as the minimalist, sanitized, color-coordinated ones you see on Pinterest. I have bad news: you and I, along with most, are not minimalist, sanitized people. Our lives are messy, dirty, and full of junk. That won’t change, but what can change is how we interact with our things.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflections on a year of biking to work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reflections-on-a-year-of-biking-to-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflections on a year of biking to work" /><published>2024-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reflections%20on%20a%20year%20of%20biking%20to%20work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reflections-on-a-year-of-biking-to-work/"><![CDATA[<p>Starting in July 2023, I biked to work five days a week, for about 2 miles each way. That comes out to somewhere around 1000 miles, maybe a bit less accounting for sick days and incidental and occasional (but appreciated) rides from my girlfriend. With a total of two bikes used (the first was stolen) this was absolutely economical and enjoyable.</p>

<p>Granted, my bicycle commute is possibly one of the most idyllic in America. Almost entirely on a designated path along a river, only on a road for the final ~30 yards. This wasn’t on accident though. I chose my apartment exclusively because of the proximity and pleasantness of the commute, and likely paid extra for it. That was a non-negotiable part of my housing choice.</p>

<p>I did this every day, rain or shine, snow or sleet, and I think some of my favorite days were the ones with the worst weather. A few highlights:</p>

<p>Drenching rain in a t-shirt soaked to the bone, passing a similarly dressed runner absolutely beaming the same way I was as my music blasted in my ears and I sprinted the full 2 miles.</p>

<p>A late freeze in January with temperatures in the teens and a thin layer of ice on the trail. Any time I put too much force into the pedals my rear wheel would spin out. Fell three times during this freeze but wouldn’t trade the experience for a more pleasant one.</p>

<p>Getting passed by a full racing peloton on my casual ride to work, and completely gassing myself to almost keep up for a few minutes.</p>

<p>None of these experiences were advisable, but they were all fulfilling, enjoyable, and mine.</p>

<p>#Creation/articles</p>]]></content><author><name>Ayyybel</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting in July 2023, I biked to work five days a week, for about 2 miles each way. That comes out to somewhere around 1000 miles, maybe a bit less accounting for sick days and incidental and occasional (but appreciated) rides from my girlfriend. With a total of two bikes used (the first was stolen) this was absolutely economical and enjoyable.]]></summary></entry></feed>